Penelope Jagessar Chaffer: I was going to ask if there's a doctor in the house.
بينيلوب جاكسار شافر: كنت سأسأل ما إذا كان هناك طبيب في المسرح
No, I'm just joking.
لا, امزح فقط
It's interesting, because it was six years ago
هذا أمرٌ مثير للانتباه لانه قبل ستة سنوات
when I was pregnant with my first child
عندما كنت حامل بطفلي الاول
that I discovered
اكتشفت
that the most commonly used preservative
ان اكثر مادة حافظة استخداما
in baby care products
في منتجات العناية بالطفل
mimics estrogen
تحاكي الإستروجين
when it gets into the human body.
عندما تدخل جسم الانسان
Now it's very easy actually
من السهل جدا الان
to get a chemical compound from products
ان تحصل على مواد كيميائية من المنتجات
into the human body through the skin.
عن طريق الجلد
And these preservatives had been found
كما أن هذه المواد الحافظه وجدت
in breast cancer tumors.
في أورام سرطان الثدي
That was the start of my journey
وكانت هذه بداية مشواري
to make this film, "Toxic Baby."
لعمل هذا الفلم، "الطفل السام"
And it doesn't take much time
ولن يتطلب الكثير من الوقت
to discover some really astonishing statistics
لكي تكتشف بعض الإحصائيات المذهله
with this issue.
لهذه المسأله
One is that you and I all have
واحدة منها هو أنه أنا وانت لدينا
between 30 to 50,000 chemicals
ما بين 30000 إلى 50000 من المواد الكيميائية
in our bodies
في اجسامنا
that our grandparents didn't have.
والتي لم تكن لدى اجدادنا
And many of these chemicals
والكثير من هذه الكميائيات
are now linked to the skyrocketing incidents
لها علاقة بالحوادث الكثيرة
of chronic childhood disease
مثل الامراض المزمنة في مرحلة الطفولة
that we're seeing across industrialized nations.
التي نشهدها في جميع أنحاء الأمم الصناعية
I'll show you some statistics.
سأريكم بعض الإحصائيات
So for example, in the United Kingdom,
فعلى سبيل المثال في الامم المتحدة
the incidence of childhood leukemia
حالات سرطان الدم في مرحلة الطفولة
has risen by 20 percent just in a generation.
ارتفعت بنسبة 20 في المئة فقط خلال جيل واحد
Very similar statistic for childhood cancer in the U.S.
إحصائية مشابهة جدا لسرطان الأطفال في الولايات المتحدة
In Canada, we're now looking at one in 10 Canadian children with asthma.
في كندا ننظرحاليا إلى واحد من كل 10 أطفال يعانون من الربو
That's a four-fold increase.
هذه زيادة اربع اضعاف عما كان الامر عليه
Again, similar story around the world.
مرة أخرى، قصة مماثلة في مختلف أنحاء العالم
In the United States,
في الولايات المتحدة
probably the most astonishing statistic
ربما اكثر الاحصائيات اثارة للدهشة
is a 600 percent increase
تمثل زيادة 600 في المئة
in autism and autistic spectrum disorders
في اضطرابات طيف التوحد والمصابين بالتوحد
and other learning disabilities.
وغيرها من امراض صعوبة التعليم
Again, we're seeing that trend
مرة اخرى نرى ذلك التوجه
across Europe, across North America.
في جميع أنحاء أوروبا، وأمريكا الشمالية.
And in Europe,
و في اوروبا
there's certain parts of Europe,
هناك أجزاء معينة من أوروبا،
where we're seeing a four-fold increase
نشهد فيها زيادة قدرها أربعة أضعاف
in certain genital birth defects.
في بعض التشوهات الخلقية التناسلية
Interestingly, one of those birth defects
ومن المثير للاهتمام، واحدة من تلك التشوهات الخلقية
has seen a 200 percent increase in the U.S.
شهدت زيادة بنسبة 200 في المئة في الولايات المتحدة
So a real skyrocketing
ارتفاع عالي جدا
of chronic childhood disease
في امراض مرحلة الطفولة المزمنة
that includes other things
وهذا يتضمن اشياء اخرى
like obesity and juvenile diabetes,
مثل السمنة ومرض السكري,
premature puberty.
البلوغ السابق لأوانه
So it's interesting for me,
حتى انها مثيرة بالنسبة لي
when I'm looking for someone who can really talk to me
عندما ابحث عن انسان ليتحدث معي
and talk to an audience about these things,
وللجمهور عن هذه الاشياء
that probably one of the most important people in the world
الذي يمكن ان يكون من اهم الناس في العالم
who can discuss toxicity in babies
بامكانه ان يناقش التسمم في الاطفال
is expert in frogs.
هو خبير في الضفادع
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Tyrone Hayes: It was a surprise to me as well
تايرون هايز: فوجئت انا ايضا
that I would be talking about pesticides,
لكوني ساتحدث عن المبيدات,
that I'd be talking about public health,
ولكوني ساتحدث عن الصحة العامة
because, in fact, I never thought I would do anything useful.
لانني, في الحقيقة, لم اتوقع فعل شيئ مفيد
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Frogs.
الضفادع
In fact, my involvement in the whole pesticide issue
في الواقع, مشاركتي في مسألة المبيدات
was sort of a surprise as well
كانت مفاجئة لي ايضا
when I was approached by the largest chemical company in the world
عندما اتت الي اكبر شركة كيمائيات في العالم
and they asked me if I would evaluate
وطلبت مني تقييم
how atrazine affected amphibians, or my frogs.
كيف ان الأترازين يٍؤثر في البرمائيات, او ضفادعي
It turns out, atrazine is the largest selling product
اتضح ان الاترازين هو المنتج الأكثر مبيعا
for the largest chemical company in the world.
لاكبر شركة كيمائيات في العالم
It's the number one contaminant
هو الملوث الاول
of groundwater, drinking water, rain water.
للمياه الجوفية, مياه الشرب, ومياه الامطار
In 2003, after my studies, it was banned in the European Union,
عام 2003, بعد ابحاثي, تم منعها في الاتحاد الاوروبي
but in that same year,
لكن في نفس السنة
the United States EPA re-registered the compound.
وكالة حماية البيئة في الولايات المتحدة اعادة تسجيل المركب
We were a bit surprised when we found out
تفاجئنا بعض الشيئ بعد ان اكتشفنا
that when we exposed frogs
انه بعد ان تتعرض الضفادع
to very low levels of atrazine -- 0.1 parts per billion --
إلى مستويات منخفضة جدا من الأترازين - 0.1 أجزاء من البليون
that it produced animals that look like this.
فأنها تنتج حيوانات تشبه هذه
These are the dissected gonads of an animal
هذه هي الغدد التناسليه المشرحة للحيوان
that has two testes, two ovaries,
لديه خصيتين ومبيضين
another large testis, more ovaries,
خصيه اخرى, والمزيد من المبايض
which is not normal ...
هذا غير طبيعي
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
even for amphibians.
حتى للبرمائيات
In some cases, another species like the North American Leopard Frog
في بعض الحالات, كائنات اخرى مثل الضفدع النمر في امريكا الشمالية
showed that males exposed to atrazine grew eggs in their testes.
اظهرت ان الذكور التي تتعرض الى الاترازين ينموا بيض في خصيتها
And you can see these large, yolked-up eggs
وبامكانك ان ترى هذه البويضات الكبيرة
bursting through the surface of this male's testes.
تنفجر خلال سطح خصيتي هذا الذكر
Now my wife tells me, and I'm sure Penelope can as well,
الان, زوجتي تقول لي, وانا متأكد بينولوب كذلك,
that there's nothing more painful than childbirth --
لا يوجد شيئ اكثر الم من الولادة --
which that I'll never experience, I can't really argue that --
والتي هي شيئ لن اشهده, لن اجادل في ذلك --
but I would guess that a dozen chicken eggs in my testicle
لكن اعتقد ان وجود دستة من بيض الدجاج في خصيتي
would probably be somewhere in the top five.
قد يكون من اكثر خمسة اشياء مسببة للألم
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
In recent studies that we've published,
في دراسات حديثة نشرناها
we've shown that some of these animals when they're exposed to atrazine,
بينا ان بعض هذه الحيوانات عند تعرضها للاترازين,
some of the males grow up
تنمو بعض الذكور
and completely become females.
وتصبح أناث بالكامل
So these are actually two brothers consummating a relationship.
هؤلاء في الحقيقة اخوان يتعاملان
And not only do these genetic males mate with other males,
وليس فقط ان هؤلاء الذكور يتزاوجوا مع ذكور اخرى,
they actually have the capacity to lay eggs
بل ان لهم القدرة على البيض
even though they're genetic males.
في حين انهم وراثيا ذكور
What we proposed,
الذي اقترحناه,
and what we've now generated support for,
والذي انشأنا دعم من اجله
is that what atrazine is doing
هو ذلك الذي يفعله الاترازين
is wreaking havoc causing a hormone imbalance.
يعيث فسادا مما تسبب في اختلال التوازن الهرموني
Normally the testes should make testosterone,
عادة الخصيتين تنتج هرمون التستوستيرون
the male hormone.
هرمون الذكور
But what atrazine does is it turns on an enzyme,
ولكن ما يفعله الاترازين هو انه يغلق هذا الانزيم
the machinery if you will, aromatase,
الة, اذا صح التعبير, الاروماتيز
that converts testosterone into estrogen.
التي تحول التستوستيرون الى هورمون الاستروجين
And as a result, these exposed males
ونتيجة لذلك فان تلك الذكور المُتعرضة
lose their testosterone, they're chemically castrated,
تفقد التستوستيرون لديها, حُزفت كيمائيا
and they're subsequently feminized
و أُنثت لاحقا
because now they're making the female hormone.
لانهم الان ينتجون هورمون الاناث
Now this is what brought me to the human-related issues.
الآن هذا هو الذي أتى بي إلى قضايا ذات صلة بالإنسان
Because it turns out
لانه تبين ان
that the number one cancer in women, breast cancer,
السرطان رقم واحد عند النساء, سرطان الثدي,
is regulated by estrogen and by this enzyme aromatase.
ينظم بواسطة هرمون الاستروجين، وهذا الانزيم ,الاروماتيز
So when you develop a cancerous cell in your breast,
لذا فعندما تنموا خلايا سرطانية في الثدي
aromatase converts androgens into estrogens,
الاروماتيز يحول الأندروجينات الى استروجين
and that estrogen turns on or promotes
وهذا الاستروجين يفتح ويثير
the growth of that cancer
نمو هذا السرطان
so that it turns into a tumor and spreads.
فيتحول الى ورم و ينتشر
In fact, this aromatase is so important in breast cancer
في الواقع, هذا الاروماتيز مهم جدا في سرطان الثدي
that the latest treatment for breast cancer
حيث ان احدث علاج لسرطان الثدي
is a chemical called letrozole,
هو كيمائي يسمى اليتروزول
which blocks aromatase, blocks estrogen,
والذي يمنع الاروماتيز و الاستروجين
so that if you developed a mutated cell, it doesn't grow into a tumor.
بحيث اذا اصبت بخلية متحولة, فانها لا تنمو و تصبح ورم
Now what's interesting is, of course,
المثير للاهتمام الان هو , بالطبع
that we're still using 80 million pounds of atrazine,
اننا ما زلنا نستخدم 80 مليون رطل من الاترازين
the number one contaminant in drinking water, that does the opposite --
الملوث الاول لمياه الشرب, و الذي يسبب العكس--
turns on aromatase, increases estrogen
يشغل الاروماتيز, يزيد الاستروجين
and promotes tumors in rats
ويعزز الاورام في الفئران
and is associated with tumors, breast cancer, in humans.
وذو صلة باالاورام, لدى الانسان
What's interesting is, in fact,
المثير للاهتمام هو، في الواقع
the same company that sold us 80 million pounds of atrazine,
نفس الشركة التي باعت لنا 80 مليون جرام من الأترازين،
the breast cancer promoter,
المثير لسرطان الثدي
now sells us the blocker -- the exact same company.
الان تبيع لنا المضاد -- هي الشركة نفسها
And so I find it interesting
لذا فانى ارى هذا شيئ يثير الإنتباه
that instead of treating this disease
هذا بدلا من علاج هذا المرض
by preventing exposure to the chemicals that promote it,
عن طريق منع التعرض للمواد الكيميائية التي تعززها،
we simply respond
استجبنا ببساطة
by putting more chemicals into the environment.
بوضع المزيد من الكيمائيات في البيئة
PJC: So speaking of estrogen,
بينيلوب: في حديثنا عن الاستروجين
one of the other compounds that Tyrone talks about in the film
من المركبات التي تحدث عنها تايرون في الفلم
is something called bisphenol A, BPA,
هو ما يسمى بالبسفينول أ
which has been in the news recently.
التي كانت في الانباء مؤخرا
It's a plasticizer.
هي من الملدنات
It's a compound that's found in polycarbonate plastic,
هو مركب وجد في بلاستيك البولي
which is what baby bottles are made out of.
والذي تصنع منه زجاجات الاطفال
And what's interesting about BPA
ومايثير الانتباه في بالبسفينول
is that it's such a potent estrogen
هو كونه استروجين قوي لدرجة
that it was actually once considered for use
انه في الواقع كان يستخدم
as a synthetic estrogen in hormone placement therapy.
كهرمون استروجين اصطناعي في العلاج الهرموني
And there have been many, many, many studies that have shown
كما وُجد الكثير, الكثير, الكثير من الابحاث التى اظهرت
that BPA leaches from babies' bottles
ان البيسفيتول يتسرب من زجاجات الاطفال
into the formula, into the milk,
الى الصيغة, الى الحليب
and therefore into the babies.
وبالتالي الى الاطفال
So we're dosing our babies,
بذلك نحن نجرع اطفالنا
our newborns, our infants,
حديثي الولادة, الرضع
with a synthetic estrogen.
استروجين اصطناعي
Now two weeks ago or so,
الان قبل اسبوعين او نحو ذلك,
the European Union passed a law
اصدر الاتحاد الاوروبي قانونا
banning the use of BPA
يمنع اسخدام البيسفيتول
in babies' bottles and sippy cups.
في زجاجات اطفالنا او اكواب السيبي
And for those of you who are not parents,
وبالنسبة لأولئك الذين ليسوا من الآباء والأمهات،
sippy cups are those little plastic things
اكواب السيبي هي تلك اشياء البلاستيك الصغيرة
that your child graduates to after using bottles.
التي يستخدمها طفلك بعد التخرج من استخدام الزجاجة
But just two weeks before that,
لكن قبل اسبوعين من ذلك
the U.S. Senate refused to even debate
رفض المجلس الامريكي الاعلى حتى مناقشة
the banning of BPA
منع استخدام البيسفيتول
in babies' bottles and sippy cups.
في زجاجات الاطفال و اكواب السيبي
So it really makes you realize
وهذا يجعلك تفهم
the onus on parents
المسؤولية التي على عاتق الآباء والأمهات
to have to look at this and regulate this and police this
في النظر الى وتنظيم ومراقبة هذا
in their own lives
في حياتهم الخاصة
and how astonishing that is.
وياله من شيئ مزهل
(Video) PJC: With many plastic baby bottles
(فيديو) بينيلوب: مع العديد من الزجاجات البلاستيكية
now proven to leak the chemical bisphenol A,
ثبت انها تثرب المادة الكيمائية بسفينول إيه
it really shows how sometimes
هذا يظهر كيف انه احيانا
it is only a parent's awareness
وعي الاباء و الامهات فقط هو الذي
that stands between chemicals and our children.
يحول مابين الكيمائيات و ابنائنا
The baby bottle scenario proves
اثبت سيناريو زجاجات الاطفال
that we can prevent unnecessary exposure.
انه يمكننا منع التعرض الغير ضروري
However, if we parents are unaware,
ومع ذلك, فاذا لم يدرك الاباء
we are leaving our children
فنحن نترك ابنائنا
to fend for themselves.
ليتدبروا امورهم بانفسهم
TH: And what Penelope says here
تايرون هايز: ما تقوله بينيلوب هنا
is even more true.
اكثر حقيقة
For those of you who don't know, we're in the middle of the sixth mass extinction.
لأولئك منكم الذين لا يعرفون، نحن في منتصف الانقراض الجماعي السادس
Scientists agree now.
اتفق العلماء الان
We are losing species from the Earth
اننا نفقد كائنات من الارض
faster than the dinosaurs disappeared,
اسرع من انقراض الديناصورات
and leading that loss are amphibians.
والبرمائيات في مقدمة هذا الانقراض
80 percent of all amphibians
80 في المائة من جميع البرمائيات
are threatened and in come decline.
مهددة وفي هبوط مستقبلا
And I believe, many scientists believe
وأعتقد، يعتقد الكثير من العلماء
that pesticides are an important part of that decline.
أن المبيدات تشكل جزءا هاما من هذا الانخفاض
In part, amphibians are good indicators and more sensitive
جزئيا, البرمائيات مؤشر جيد واكثر حساسية
because they don't have protection from contaminants in the water --
لانها لا تملك حماية ضد ملوثات المياه
no eggshells, no membranes
لاقشر بيض ولا غشاء
and no placenta.
ولا مشيمة
In fact, our invention -- by "our" I mean we mammals --
في الواقع, تكويننا -- وبـ"نحن" اقصد نحن الثديات --
one of our big inventions was the placenta.
من عظائم تكويننا هي المشيمة
But we also start out as aquatic organisms.
لكن بدأنا ايضا ككائنات مائية
But it turns out that this ancient structure
ولكن تبين أن هذا الهيكل القديم
that separates us from other animals, the placenta,
الذي يفصل بيننا وبين الحيوانات الأخرى، المشيمة،
cannot evolve or adapt fast enough
لا يمكنه أن يتطور أو يتكيف بسرعة كافية
because of the rate that we're generating new chemicals
بسبب سرعة الكيمائيات الجدبدة التي نولدها
that it's never seen before.
والتي لم يرها من قبل
The evidence of that is that studies in rats, again with atrazine,
والدليل على ذلك, دراسات اجريت على الفئران, مرة ثانبة مع الاترازين
show that the hormone imbalance atrazine generates causes abortion.
اظهرت ان عدم التوازن الهرموني الذي يسببه الاترازين يسبب الاجهاض
Because maintaining a pregnancy is dependent on hormones.
لأن الحفاظ على الحمل يعتمد على الهرمونات
Of those rats that don't abort,
من تلك الفئران التي لا تجهض،
atrazine causes prostate disease
الأترازين تسبب امراض البروستات
in the pups so the sons
في الجراء ولذا فإن الابناء
are born with an old man's disease.
يولدون بمرض الرجل العجوز
Of those that don't abort,
واما اولائك اللاتي لا يجهضن
atrazine causes impaired mammary, or breast, development
فان الاترزين يسبب ضعف الثدي، أو سرطان الثدي، والتنمية
in the exposed daughters in utero,
في البنات المتعرضة داخل الرحم
so that their breast don't develop properly.
لذلك فثديها لا تنموا بشكل صحيح
And as a result, when those rats grow up,
ونتيجة لذلك, عندما تكبر هذه الفئران
their pups experience retarded growth and development
فان الجراء تعاني من تأخر في التنمية والنمو
because they can't make enough milk to nourish their pups.
لأنه لا يمكنهما تقديم ما يكفي من الحليب لتغذية صغارها
So the pup you see on the bottom is affected by atrazine
لذا فان الجرو الذي تراه في الاسفل, تأثر بالاترزين
that its grandmother was exposed to.
الذي تعرضت اليه الجدة
And given the life of many of these chemicals,
ونظرا لحياة كثير من هذه المواد الكيميائية
generations, years, dozens of years,
أجيال، سنوات، عشرات السنين،
that means that we right now
هذا يعني اننا الان
are affecting the health
نؤثر على صحة
of our grandchildren's grandchildren
احفاد احفادنا
by things that we're putting into the environment today.
بالاشياء التي نضعها في البيئة اليوم
And this is not just philosophical, it's already known,
وهذه ليست مجرد فلسفة وانما , معروفة فعلا
that chemicals like diethylstilbestrol and estrogen,
أن المواد الكيميائية مثل ثنائي إيثيل ستيلبوستيرول والاستروجين،
PCBs, DDT
كلورو ثنائى الفينيل, و د.د.ت
cross the placenta
تعبر المشيمة
and effectively determine
ويحدد بفعالية
the likelihood of developing breast cancer
احتمال الاصابة بسرطان الثدي
and obesity and diabetes
والسمنة ومرض السكري
already when the baby's in the womb.
مسبقا عند وجود الطفل في الرحم
In addition to that, after the baby's born,
بالاضافة لذلك, بعد ولادة الطفل
our other unique invention as mammals
تكويننا الفريد كثديات
is that we nourish our offspring after they're born.
هو اننا نغذي اولادنا بعد الولادة
We already know that chemicals
ما نعرفه ان الكيميائيات
like DDT and DES and atrazine
دى.دى .تى و داي إتيل ستلبسترول و الاترازين
can also pass over into milk,
يمكنها الانتقال الى الحليب
again, affecting our babies
ومرة اخرى مؤثرا على اولادنا
even after their born.
حتى بعد الولادة
PJC: So when Tyrone tells me
بينيلوب: عندما يخبرني تايرون
that the placenta is an ancient organ,
ان المشيمة جهاز قديم
I'm thinking, how do I demonstrate that?
أفكر, كيف بامكاني اثبات ذلك
How do you show that?
كيف تظهر ذلك؟
And it's interesting when you make a film like this,
وصنع فلم لمثل هذا الامر مثير للاهتمام
because you're stuck trying to visualize science
لانك تتعلق محاولا تصور العلم
that there's no visualization for.
الذي لايوجد له تصوير
And I have to take a little bit of artistic license.
وعلي اخذ رخصة فنية صغيرة
(Video) (Ringing)
(فلم) (رنين)
Old man: Placenta control.
رجل كبير السن: مراقبة المشيمة
What is it?
ما هذا؟
Oh what?
ماذا؟
(Snoring)
(شخير)
(Honk)
(تزمير)
Puffuffuff, what?
بوفوفوفوف, ماذا؟
Perflourooctanoic acid.
الحامض المشبع
Blimey.
و ماذا بعد
Never heard of it.
لم اسمع به من قبل
PJC: And neither had I actually
بينيلوب: حقيقة, ولا انا
before I started making this film.
قبل الشروع بعمل هذا الفلم
And so when you realize that chemicals can pass the placenta
وهكذا عندما تدرك ان الكيميائيات بامكانها اختراق المشيمة
and go into your unborn child,
وتذهب الى ابنك الذي لم يولد بعد
it made me start to think,
جعلني افكر
what would my fetus say to me?
مالذي سيقوله لي الجنين
What would our unborn children say to us
مالذي يقوله اطفالنا الذين لم يولدوا لنا
when they have an exposure
عندما يحدث لهم التعرض
that's happening everyday, day after day?
الذي يحدث كل يوم, يوم بعد اخر
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Video) Child: Today,
(فيلم) طفل: اليوم
I had some octyphenols,
تعاطيت بعض الاوكتيفينول
some artificial musks
بعض المسك الاصطناعي
and some bisphenol A.
وبعض البسفينول إيه
Help me.
ساعدوني.
PJC: It's a very profound notion
بينيلوب: هي فكرة عميقة جدا
to know that we as women
لنعلم اننا كنساء
are at the vanguard of this.
نحن في المقدمة من هذا
This is our issue,
هذه قضيتنا
because we collect these compounds our entire life
لاننا نجمع هذه المركبات طيلة حياتنا
and then we end up dumping it and dumping them
وفي النهاية نرمي بها جميعها عليهم
into our unborn children.
إلى أطفالنا الذين لم يولدوا بعد
We are in effect
نحن في الواقع
polluting our children.
نلوث اطفالنا
And this was something that was really brought home to me a year ago
وكان هذا شيئ وجدته في منزلي قبل عام
when I found out I was pregnant
عندما اكتشفت انني حامل
and the first scan revealed
وكشف اول فحص
that my baby had a birth defect
ان طفلي به عيب خلقي
associated with exposure
مرتبط بالتعرض
to estrogenic chemicals in the womb
لمواد كيميائية استروجينية داخل الرحم
and the second scan
الفحص الثاني
revealed no heartbeat.
كشف عدم وجود نبضات قلب
So my child's death, my baby's death,
لذا وفاة إبني، وفاة طفلي،
really brought home the resonance of what I was trying to make in this film.
هي التي اتت بصدى ما كنت احاول عمله في هذا الفلم
And it's sometimes a weird place
واحيانا يكون غريب
when the communicator becomes part of the story,
عندما يصبح المتصل جزءا من القصة
which is not what you originally intend.
وليس هذا ما تنويه
And so when Tyrone talks about
ولذلك عندما يتحدث تايرون عن
the fetus being trapped in a contaminated environment,
وقوع الجنين في بيئة ملوثة،
this is my contaminated environment.
هذه بيئتي انا الملوثة
This is my toxic baby.
هذا طفلي انا الملوث
And that's something
وهذا شيئ
that's just profound and sad,
فقط عميق ومحزن
but astonishing
ولكن مدهش
because so many of us don't actually know this.
لأن الكثير منا في الواقع لا يعرف ذلك
TH: One of this things that's exciting and appropriate
تايرون: احد تلك الاشياء المثيرة والملائمة
for me to be here at TEDWomen
لا كون هنا في مؤتمر تيد للنساء
is that, well, I think it was summed up best last night at dinner
انه, اعتقد انها لُخصت باكمل وجه ليلة امس في العشاء
when someone said, "Turn to the man at your table and tell them,
عندما قال احدهم, "التفتِ الى الرجل الذي على طاولتِك واخبريه"
'When the revolution starts, we've got your back.'"
"سندعمكم عندما تبدأ الثورة"
The truth is, women,
الحقيقة هي, النساء
you've had our back on this issue for a very long time,
دعمتومونا دائما في هذه القضية لوقت طويل,
starting with Rachel Carson's "Silent Spring"
بدأَ بـ "الربيع الصامت" لراشيل كارسون
to Theo Colborn's "Our Stolen Future"
الى "مستقبلنا المسروق" لثيو كولبورن
to Sandra Steingraber's books
الى كتب ساندرا شتاينبراغر
"Living Downstream" and "Having Faith."
"العيش مع التيار" و "وجود الايمان"
And perhaps it's the connection to our next generation --
وربما كان هذا اتصال مع الاجيال القادمة
like my wife and my beautiful daughter here about 13 years ago --
مثل زوجتي و ابنتي منذ حوالي 13 عاما --
perhaps it's that connection
ربما يكون هذا الاتصال
that makes women activists
هو الذي يصنع نساء ناشطات
in this particular area.
في هذا المجال خاصة.
But for the men here, I want to say
ولكن بالنسبة للرجال هنا، أريد أن أقول
it's not just women and children that are at risk.
ليس المرأة والطفل فقط من هما في خطر
And the frogs that are exposed to atrazine,
والضفادع التي تتعرض لالأترازين
the testes are full of holes and spaces,
الخصيتين مليئة بالثغرات والمساحات
because the hormone imbalance,
لأن الخلل الهرموني,
instead of allowing sperm to be generated,
بدلا من السماح بتوليد الحيوانات المنوية،
such as in the testis here,
مثل الذي في الخصية هنا
the testicular tubules end up empty
الأنابيب الخصية تصبح فارغة
and fertility goes down by as much as 50 percent.
وتنخفض الخصوبة بنسبة تصل إلى 50 في المئة
It's not just my work in amphibians,
ليس هذا مجرد عملي مع البرمائيات
but similar work has been shown in fish in Europe,
ولكن ثبت بأعمال مماثلة في الأسماك في أوروبا،
holes in the testes and absence of sperm in reptiles in a group from South America
ثقوب في الخصيتين وعدم وجود الحيوانات المنوية في الزواحف في مجموعة من أمريكا الجنوبية
and in rats, an absence of sperm
وعدم وجود حيوانات منوية في الفئران
in the testicular tubules as well.
وكذلك في الأنابيب الخصية
And of course, we don't do these experiments in humans,
وطبعا نحن لا نقوم بهذه التجارب على البشر،
but just by coincidence,
ولكن بالصدفة,
my colleague has shown
اظهر زميلي
that men who have low sperm count, low semen quality
أن الرجال الذين لديهم انخفاض في الحيوانات المنوية، وإنخفاض في جودة السائل المنوي
have significantly more atrazine in their urine.
لديهم الأترازين أكثر بكثير في البول
These are just men who live
ليس اولئك سوى رجال يعيشون
in an agricultural community.
في مجتمع زراعي
Men who actually work in agriculture
الرجال الذين يعملون فعلا في الزراعة
have much higher levels of atrazine.
لديهم مستويات أعلى بكثير من الأترازين
And the men who actually apply atrazine
والرجال الذين يضعون الاترازين
have even more atrazine in their urine,
لديهم اترازين اكثر في البول
up to levels that are 24,000 times what we know to be active
يصل مستوى 24,000 مرة من الذي نعرفه بكونه نشيط
are present in the urine of these men.
يوجد في بول هؤلاء الرجال
Of course, most of them, 90 percent are Mexican, Mexican-American.
وطبعا، معظمهم، 90 في المئة من المكسيكيين، المكسيكية الأمريكية
And it's not just atrazine they're exposed to.
وهم لا يتعرضون فقط للاترازين
They're exposed to chemicals like chloropicrin,
هم يتعرضون للمواد الكيميائيات مثل الكلوروبكرين،
which was originally used as a nerve gas.
والذي كان يستخدم اصلا كغاز للاعصاب
And many of these workers
والكثير من اولئك العمال
have life expectancies of only 50.
متوسط العمر لديهم هو 50 سنة فقط
It shouldn't come to any surprise that the things that happen in wildlife
ليس مستغربا ان الاشياء التي تحدث في الحياة البرية
are also a warning to us,
هي ايضا تحذرنا
just like Rachel Carson and others have warned.
تماما كما حذرت راشيل كارسون وغيرها.
As evident in this slide from Lake Nabugabo in Uganda,
كما موضح في هذه الصفحة من بحيرة نابوقابو في أوغندا,
the agricultural runoff from this crop,
ومياه الصرف الزراعي من هذه المحاصيل،
which goes into these buckets,
التي تذهب إلى هذه الدلاء،
is the sole source of drinking, cooking and bathing water for this village.
فهو المصدر الوحيد لمياه الشرب والطهي والاستحمام لهذه القرية
Now if I told the men in this village
الآن إذا قلت للرجال في هذه القرية
that the frogs have pour immune function
أن الضفادع لديها وظائف مناعة ضعيفة
and eggs developing in their testes,
وبيض ينمو في خصيتيهم
the connection between environmental health and public health
العلاقة ما بين صحة البيئة والصحة العامة
would be clear.
ستكون واضحة
You would not drink water that you knew was having this kind of impact
انت لن تشرب هذا الماء اذا علمت ان به هذا النوع من التأثير
on the wildlife that lived in it.
على الحياة البرية التي تعيش فيها
The problem is, in my village, Oakland,
المشكلة هي، في قريتي، أوكلاند،
in most of our villages,
في معظم قرانا،
we don't see that connection.
لا نرى تلك العلاقة
We turn on the faucet, the water comes out, we assume it's safe,
نشغل الحنفية، ويخرج الماء، ونحن نعتبرها آمنة،
and we assume that we are masters of our environment,
نحن نظن اننا اسياد بيئتنا,
rather than being part of it.
بدلا من أن تكون جزءا منها.
PJC: So it doesn't take much to realize
بينيلوب: انه لا يحتاج الكثير لفهم
that actually this is an environmental issue.
ان هذه في الحقيقة قضية بيئية
And I kept thinking over and over again
وظللت أفكر مرارا وتكرارا
this question.
في هذا السؤال
We know so much about global warming and climate change,
نحن نعرف الكثير عن ظاهرة الاحتباس الحراري وتغير المناخ،
and yet, we have no concept
وحتى الآن، ليس لدينا أي فكرة
of what I've been calling internal environmentalism.
ما اسميه بحماية البيئة الداخلية.
We know what we're putting out there,
نحن نعلم ما نضعه هناك
we have a sense of those repercussions,
ولدينا شعور بتلك العواقب,
but we are so ignorant of this sense
ولكن نحن نجهل جدا بهذا الشعور
of what happens when we put things, or things are put
بما سيحدث عندما نضع الاشياء, تُوضع الاشياء
into our bodies.
داخل اجسامنا.
And it's my feeling
وهو احساسي
and it's my urging being here
والحاحي لكوني هنا
to know that, as we women move forward
لمعرفة, اننا النساء نتقدم للامام
as the communicators of this,
كاعلاميين بهذا
but also as the ones who carry that burden
ولكن ايضا كحاملي هذا العبئ
of carrying the children, bearing the children,
بحمل الاطفال و تحملهم
we hold most of the buying power in the household,
نملك اكبر قوة شرائية في المنزل
is that it's going to be us moving forward
اننا نحن اللاتي سيمضين قدما
to carry the work of Tyrone and other scientists around the world.
لدعم اعمال تايرون و غيره من العلماء حول العالم
And my urging is
وما الح اليه هو
that when we think about environmental issues
اننا عندما نفكر في القضايا البيئية
that we remember that it's not just about melting glaciers and ice caps,
علينا أن نتذكر أنها ليست فقط عن ذوبان الانهار الجليدية والغطاء الجليدي،
but it's also about our children as well.
وانما كذلك عن اطفالنا.
Thank you.
شكرا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)